Earlier this year, we crossed
$20,000,000 in lifetime sales as a
writing education business. To give you
some context, this is the aggregate
amount generated from the following
verticals. So, Ship 30 for 30, Premium
Ghostwriting Academy, Write With AI, and
our Digital Writing School. About a year
and a half ago, I wrote a similar
reflection piece on 10 lessons learned
selling $10,000,000 worth of digital
education products. But, a lot has
changed in our business since then. You
know, our portfolio of writing education
businesses grew from 10 full-time team
members to more than 30 full-time team
members. Our yearly revenue went from 6
million a year to over 8 million a year
spread across these different verticals.
Our operational complexity, especially
running our Premium Ghostwriting
Academy, is five or 10 times what it was
a year ago. And we transitioned from
being 100% dependent upon organic
traffic to adding in paid ads. So, over
the past year, we've probably spent
upwards of a million dollars on paid
ads. So, I thought it would be helpful
to take a breath here at the 20 million
lifetime revenue milestone. Uh we're
above it now. And share some of our
biggest learnings. If you run or have an
interest in building a digital education
business, I hope that this helps you on
your own journey cuz we've learned a lot
of lessons the hard way. And if you want
help scaling your own digital education
business, I'd love to work with you
inside of our AI writing school. Lesson
number one, subjectivity doesn't scale.
So, anytime someone says to me, "I want
to scale my business." The first thing
that I try to identify is what about
their business is currently subjective.
Because oftentimes, subjectivity hides
in plain sight. So, an example would be,
say you run an agency and you have one
account manager who interfaces with
clients. And they're great. They work
hard, clients are happy, and you think
it's time to scale. The problem is a lot
about that account manager's role hasn't
yet been defined. It hasn't been made
objective. They do what they do
intuitively. So, not based on a
prescriptive checklist or a set of
processes that you've built. And if you
don't have these clearly defined
processes, then you can't scale this
person's role. They also keep clients
happy because of bundled traits. They're
personable or they're reliable. But
these traits are bundled terms, meaning
unless you can unbundle them into
repeatable actions, you can't actually
scale this person's personality. And
then the third is they solve problems
based on their own level of personal
motivation. So, maybe they're really
proactive because that's a quality that
they value about themselves. But if this
person's role is not gamified properly
with clear incentives that reward the
right behaviors and disincentivize the
wrong behaviors, then you can't actually
scale this person's level of motivation,
right? Cuz it's going to be different
with the next person that you hire. So,
on the surface, a great hire masks a lot
of these problems. And it's not until
you start unbundling their role and
their motivations and their reward
system and even their personality that
you begin to realize the level of
specificity that you need to achieve in
order to successfully scale someone's
role within a company. Subjectivity
doesn't scale. Lesson number two, if
traffic is concentrated, you should
scale vertically. And if traffic is
decentralized, then you can scale
horizontally. So, the amount of things
you can sell your audience is dependent
upon whether the traffic you generate is
concentrated or decentralized. So,
concentrated traffic means one personal
brand building one email list. And
decentralized traffic means multiple
personal brands building multiple
different email lists. For example, in
early 2026, we thought that we could
scale our business even further
horizontally by promoting a few people
internally within our company to lead
programs of their own. And we thought,
okay, more offers equals more money. The
problem is these team members we
elevated didn't have audiences of their
own. Traffic wasn't decentralized. It
was still concentrated, which meant that
their offers were dependent on our
audiences, which ended up competing with
our own offers. So, we learned the hard
way that if traffic is concentrated to a
single personal brand or, in our case,
my personal brand and Dickie's personal
brand and one email list, then scaling
horizontally doesn't work. You don't
actually gain more. All that happens is
you present your customers with more
choices and it ends up cannibalizing
your core business. This is different
than what a company like Agora Financial
has been able to achieve. So, their
education business and the traffic they
generate is not concentrated to one
personal brand. Their traffic is
decentralized. Each personal brand and
each thought leader has their own
audience and their own credibility,
which can then be monetized with their
own stack of offers. So, if I was trying
to scale horizontally again, what I
would look to do is partner with
tangentially related creators who have
built their own audiences in similar but
different niches. And then I would focus
on just helping them with the back end,
with operations, with offer
construction, and with LTV extension.
But you can do that because they are
decentralized, right? They aren't
cannibalizing your personal brand or
your core offer. Lesson number three, it
takes about 20 live webinars to figure
out how to make a webinar ROI positive.
In 2025, we decided that we wanted to
try to scale PGA with paid ads and live
webinars. The first webinar we ran was
really just a forcing function for us to
get a rep in. The measure for success
anytime you do something the first time
is quite literally to just do it. So,
that's all we focused on. The second
webinar was a container to fix
everything that broke during the first
webinar. So, you got to do the second
rep to learn and fix all the things that
you figured out the first time. And then
the third webinar was really the first
rep where we knew enough that we could
start to iterate and improve. But if I'm
being completely honest, it took upwards
of 20 weekly webinars to get it right.
So, that's almost five straight months
of running a weekly webinar. Each
webinar was two, two and a half hours.
It was the same slides, sharing the same
stories, and the same insights. We're
answering the same questions. We were
giving the same pitch. And still, like
it took 20 iterations before we felt
like we had gotten it to a point where
we could rely on it to perform at a
certain level. And I share that because
if you're thinking about scaling with
paid ads and or webinars, I want to
level set your expectations. Because
before we held that first webinar, I
thought, "Oh, great. We'll just do this
once or twice, and then it'll be on
repeat. Like it'll be done." And that is
not what happened. And I feel
>> [laughter]
>> very stupid for thinking that that was
what was going to happen. We changed the
positioning of the webinar a dozen
times. I rewrote and rebuilt the slides
of the webinar a dozen times. We held so
many webinars week after week that I
started to lose my voice. So, that said,
okay, if you're willing to put in the
work, I can tell you webinars can
perform very, very well. And now we view
them as one of the highest ROI vehicles
for acquiring new customers into our
ecosystem of writing programs. That's
because they're incredibly effective at
educating one-to-many people live, all
at the same time. But, it comes with a
lot of work. Lesson number four, the
more money you make, the more likely you
are to spend money on the wrong things.
Everyone loves to believe that more
money would solve their current
problems. But, the reality is the reason
you have the problems you have is
because you cannot effectively manage
your current resources. So, more money
doesn't make those problems go away. In
fact, it is quite the opposite. More
money just increases the likelihood that
you will spend money on the wrong
things. Some of the worst hires I've
ever made were during periods where our
business was generating the most revenue
and the most profit. And some of the
best hires that I've ever made were
during periods where our business was
very small and very lean, and I was
being very conscious and critical of
every single person I brought on. And
that's because when someone's monthly
salary is a rounding error for the
business, you don't scrutinize the
decision as much, especially when you're
growing and you're growing fast. It's so
much easier, especially when you're
stressed, to just say, "Eh, whatever,
we'll just hire someone. They'll do it."
But when you remove all that excess cash
flow and you ask yourself the same
question, you know, would I hire this
person? All of a sudden, you realize,
"No, I would not." And this is why you
hear entrepreneurs talk so much about
fighting to stay small. No matter how
much you grow, you want to try to make
level-headed hiring decisions as if you
were still that small lean cash
conscious company. The nuance is, yes,
often times you have to spend money to
make money, or invest in talent
proactively in order to grow to the next
level. So, I'm not advocating for
frugality. I am reminding myself and
sharing this to scrutinize the ROI of
each person I hire, regardless of
whether or not their cost is a rounding
error for the business. Every dollar
counts. Lesson number five, limit sales
people's commissions to their current
employment. This is a pretty specific
lesson that really only applies if you
run a high-ticket group coaching program
or agency or B2B business where you have
some sort of sales team, but it was a
painful one for us, so figured I'd
share. When you hire sales people, they
are typically paid on commission. And if
you need to limit their downside, you
should do what's called a draw, which is
where you protect their downside while
letting them keep their upside. So, this
passes the risk along to the business
instead of the individual. So, here's
how it works. A typical draw would be
like three grand to five grand per
month. Think of this as their salary.
The salesperson gets this draw, so say
three grand a month, no matter what. So,
this protects their downside. But, they
do not unlock their upside until they
generate three grand in commissions for
themselves. So, this makes their draw
similar to like an advance. For high
performers, the draw doesn't matter
because they're going to recoup and
exceed their draw every month anyways.
But for low performers, the draw gives
them some runway to figure things out.
But if two or three months goes by and
they aren't able to out-earn their draw,
the answer is pretty clear that they
aren't a good fit. The reason that you
have a draw is primarily for the first
one to three months of onboarding a new
sales rep to mitigate their downside
while they get trained. I digress. The
lesson is that when you provide sales
people with an employment contract,
you want to explicitly state that they
only receive commissions as long as they
are actively employed by the company. So
this prevents a few things. First, it
simplifies accounting. You do not want
to be continuing to track monthly
payouts for people that you no longer
even employ. Second, it prevents sales
people from selling and bailing. Every
so often, you'll run into a salesperson
who gets a little liberal overpromising
customers, and then if when they leave,
you're stuck paying them out for a
customer who may end up being unhappy.
They might ask for a refund 30 days
later. I want to say this is rare,
doesn't really happen that often, but
when it does happen, it's one of those
things where you want to kick yourself.
Third is it acts as a retention
mechanism. So selling customers on
recurring contracts or payment plans is
a bit like a salesperson building up
their own book of business and recurring
revenue. And eventually, what happens is
there is no incentive for them to stay
if they can just take all that revenue
with them. So you want the stickiness of
the revenue to be a motivator for them
to stick around. We made this mistake
with the first handful of sales people
we hired for PGA, and it cost us tens of
thousands of dollars in commissions that
we shouldn't have had to pay out, but
didn't explicitly name in our employment
agreements. Lesson number six, you can
do more way, way longer than you think.
One of my favorite Hormozi frameworks is
more, better, new. So first, do more. Do
as much as you possibly can. Then when
you've maxed out effort, do it better,
better, and better, and better. And then
and only then, when you're doing as much
as you can, as best as you can, should
you consider doing something new or
different. Unfortunately, I have
continued to learn the hard lesson that
you can do more way, way longer than you
think. So let me walk you through this
very slowly cuz this is taking me a long
time to understand. Whenever you reach
some sort of ceiling or plateau, it is
very easy to believe that you have maxed
out your opportunity vehicle. You think
there is no way that you can do more.
But, the truth is you think that you've
plateaued because you haven't yet been
exposed to the next level of more. It's
kind of like being a middle school
basketball player and thinking there is
no way I could work harder. But, then
one day you go train with the high
school kids and you realize, "Hang on a
second, there is a completely different
level of effort that is available to
me." So, we experienced this. We've
experienced it in a lot of different
ways, but we experienced this when we
joined Alex Hormozi's ACQ workshop. And
you think you're running so many ads
until you sit in a room and hear someone
explain how they're running literally a
hundred times more ads than you. You
think you're hiring so many people until
you sit in a room and hear someone
explain how they're hiring ten times
more people ten times faster than you.
You think that you have such high
standards until you sit in a room and
hear someone explain their standards.
Then you realize that their standards
are way higher than your standards. And
you think that you're working so hard
until you sit in a room and hear someone
explain that their day starts earlier
than yours and ends later than yours.
So, the point is anytime you feel like
you've reached a more plateau, the
answer is not actually to jump to doing
something better or especially not
something new. The first answer is to
find an environment that challenges your
definition of more. Because chances are,
however you are defining the max of
whatever thing you're doing is wrong.
Lesson number seven, when you reach a
better plateau, the impulse is to pick
something new, which is a mistake. When
you have sufficiently maxed out more of
something, the next step is to do it
better. The problem with better is that
it's incremental improvement. So, doing
something better is usually not some
giant action or giant decision or big
change. Better is more likely to be a
thousand tiny upgrades made one at a
time, none of which, by the way, in the
moment lead to an exponential outcome.
But, all of them added together over a
prolonged period of time do. So, as
Hormozi puts it, it's a thousand golden
BBs and not one silver bullet, which
means better requires a lot of patience
and a lot of consistency, two things
that human beings are historically very
bad at. As a result, as soon as you
begin down the better path, the
incremental improvement path, you are
quickly confronted by a handful of very
painful realities. This is boring. This
is tedious. This is monotonous. This is
going to take forever. All of these
things are what cause so many people,
myself included, to come to this faulty
conclusion that they should do something
else. So, they think they should start
something new, and that is almost always
the mistake. The reason I say it's a
mistake, and I continue to learn this
lesson myself, is because people stop
pursuing the better path for only two
reasons. First, they get bored, they get
frustrated, they lose interest, or
second, more commonly, they don't know
how to do better anymore. When this
happens and you decide that the right
decision is to start something new, you
actually create two different problems
for yourself at the same time. So, when
you pick something new, first, you start
over. You're solving for boredom with
novelty, which feels really good in the
short term, but very quickly loops you
right back to where you were before. And
second, you deprive yourself of learning
the even better way to do what you were
doing before. So, the higher you climb,
the better you get at something, the
more nuanced the next improvement is,
and sometimes you need to spend two or
three months consuming lots of different
thought patterns and different
information and different ideas and
different perspectives to learn how to
do what you're already doing a little
bit better. The problem, though, is once
you start something new, well, now you
have a new commitment. So, a few few
later, when you finally realize how to
do the thing that you were doing before
better, now you can't do it. You don't
have the time. You don't have the
bandwidth because you've already started
prioritizing something else, something
new, which is why I have set a new
little rule for myself. Anytime I reach
a better plateau, I will not start
something new unless I have given myself
at least 3 months of trying as hard as
possible to expose myself to whatever
the next level of better might look like
in my current chosen domain. 99% of the
time, when you give yourself this space
to discover how to raise your own
standard, the answer becomes very clear.
And the better you get at something, the
more you actually learn how many more
levels of better there are above you.
Very rarely, 1% of the time, is the
right answer to give up, start over, and
choose something completely new and
different. Lesson number eight, there is
no one right way to drive traffic to a
business. There are so many different
playbooks that work right now to drive
traffic. You could build an entire
business off of YouTube organic. You
could build an entire business off of
just Instagram ads. You could build an
entire business using LinkedIn cold
outreach. You could build an entire
business as a TikTok shop affiliate. You
could build an entire business running
live webinars. The list of things that
you can do is literally endless. But
something that we come back to over and
over again inside our own business is
committing to play the game and running
the playbook that we know works for us
cuz there is no one right answer. And I
promise the grass is always greener. It
is so easy to see someone else
succeeding online running a completely
different marketing playbook as you and
thinking, "Oh, I should do that. I bet
their model is so much better. I bet
they don't have any of the problems I
have." And none of that is true. As a
mentor used to say to me all the time,
he would say, "Cole, you're going to
have a bag of problems either way. You
just get to pick the bag. There is no
marketing playbook that is devoid of
risk, volatility, or some level of this
is really annoying." Which means the
game isn't to bounce around and try
every new playbook of the month. Just
commit to a platform or commit to a
style of marketing and use it to build a
great business for yourself. You do not
have to do everything. Just do the one
thing that works for you. Lesson number
nine, if you don't see traction with the
budget version,
don't spend the money on the premium
version. The marketing channel that has
taught me the most about budget
allocation has to be YouTube. Everyone
loves to believe, myself included, that
the secret to YouTube is high production
quality and a pro-grade at-home setup
and a teleprompter and a fancy camera
and a script writer and a thumbnail
designer. The reality though is none of
these things matter if A, the content
isn't helpful or entertaining, depending
on what your niche is, and B, you are
awkward on camera. So, I have now
published over 1,400 videos on my
YouTube channel and I can tell you that
many of my highest performing videos
actually have the lowest production
quality. For example, little story here.
Earlier this year, we doubled our entire
video production team and started
investing heavily into YouTube. So, we
hired a head of video content, we hired
a lead editor, we hired a thumbnail
designer, we had multiple shorts
editors, and once a month we would
spend, you know, five grand renting a
huge Airbnb property here in Arizona to
film an entire month's worth of content
in eight hours. I'd just wake up and
just rip eight straight hours of videos.
All together, our monthly video
production team costs were probably in
the ballpark of around $50,000 a month
and the videos looked awesome. Like, it
was really cool. We captured a lot of
epic looking content until one day I
recorded a Loom video and published it
onto my YouTube channel myself. And that
Loom YouTube video outperformed almost
every single high production video that
we had just filmed, edited, and
published over the prior three months,
which suddenly raises the question, what
am I spending 50 grand a month for? Now,
obviously, there is an intangible cost
to building a brand and you can make the
argument that high production quality
content builds a stronger relationship
with customers or up-levels the
perceived value of the brand, blah,
blah, blah. The point is still the same.
Whenever someone asks me how they can
get started on YouTube or which camera
they should buy, the first thing I tell
them is to not buy anything. You should
just record 100 Loom videos of you
talking over a Google Doc or a Notion
Doc. And the reason is because in the
beginning, you need to build a few
skills. So first, you need to do it
consistently. You need to prove to
yourself that YouTube is a priority. Do
you know how many people say, "Oh, I
want to start prioritizing YouTube." and
then they make two videos and then they
stop. This is a skill that needs to be
built. The second is you need to clarify
your own thinking for video. Video is a
very different medium and you can do
that with just a Google Doc. You don't
need fancy cameras to clarify your
thinking for a video. And third is you
need to practice speaking on camera,
which does not require a professional
camera. There is literally zero point in
increasing your video production costs
when you haven't built the most basic
skills or seen any traction from your
efforts. Because if you can't do it with
the budget version, trust me, not going
to be able to do it with the premium
version. And this is coming from someone
who has spent over $100,000 building
this home studio. I would still tell
myself the same thing. Start with 100
Loom videos. And this lesson applies to
everything. Lesson number 10, you can't
automate what you can't articulate. The
biggest benefit I've gotten from using
AI has nothing to do with AI itself. The
more I use AI, the more I realize that I
am building the skill of prompting. Not
prompting AI, but prompting action. Who
takes the action is irrelevant. It could
be a robot, it could be a human.
Prompting is the skill of articulating
what it is you want done, how you want
it done, and how you define when it has
been done successfully. I've been
building education products and programs
for over 6 years now. And after teaching
tens of thousands of students about how
to write in the digital age, I have
accumulated a tremendous amount of
pattern recognition around which actions
lead to which results and which actions
lead to overthinking or procrastination
or lack of progress. And whenever I
think about the AI era we're in and
where AI is headed, I always come back
to the things that I've observed within
our own writing programs. Most people
want the shortcut, but the shortcut is
always the longer road in disguise. Most
people want to believe that there's a
secret key on the keyboard that makes
everything easy and automatic. And yes,
some things will get easier, but the
work isn't going to go away. The work is
just going to move somewhere else.
Everything takes work. And third, most
people call AI slop because they can't
define what not slop is in the first
place, which has nothing to do with AI.
Everything to do with their own lack of
clarity. All of these things are
starting to create a pattern that I'm
noticing over and over again, where the
more people try to skip the short-term
pain of learning how to clearly
articulate a thought or an insight or a
story or a task, the more they give up
the long-term gain of combining that
clarity of thinking with AI leverage.
Because you can't automate what you
can't articulate. Lesson 11. When you
find a marketing tactic that works, do
as much of it as you can. Especially if
your business is built on organic
marketing, the entire name of the game
is finding platform arbitrage
opportunities to generate high-quality
leads. So, for example, back in 2021,
2022, Twitter's algorithm prioritized
threads. These were long listicles
consisting of like 10 or 20 tweets all
strung together. If you saw this trend
and you built the skill of writing
viral-worthy threads, you could generate
millions of views and tens of thousands
of email subscribers with relatively low
effort. I know because we did. And this
is how we built Ship 30 for 30 into a
multi-seven-figure writing program in
its first 2 years. All we did was write
daily threads on Twitter and send people
at the end to our free email course,
Start Writing Online. But marketing
tactics don't stick around for very
long. So, by 2023, after Elon bought
Twitter and renamed it to X, threads
basically went extinct. But I have been
writing online since 2007. I have seen
dozens of these little marketing cycles
where a tactic absolutely crushes for
like 12 to 24 months and then completely
disappears. So, by the time the Twitter
algorithm changed, we were already onto
the next platform. In 2023, we started
republishing our most proven ideas and
content on LinkedIn in the form of
carousels, the next viral-worthy format,
and LinkedIn very quickly started
outperforming X in terms of lead
generation for us, even though our X
audiences were like three to five times
bigger. The point is, whenever you find
a marketing tactic that works, do not
take it for granted. Recognize that you
have just stumbled upon an arbitrage
opportunity, and you should do as much
of that marketing mechanism as possible
as fast as possible, because it is not
going to last forever. And if you want
to know what marketing tactic has been
working the best for us and many other
creators right now, it's viral drops.
So, we've been running these on X and
LinkedIn and even Substack for the past
year, sometimes multiple times a week. A
viral drop is where you package together
some sort of asset for your target
audience and then send it to them in
exchange for commenting and engaging
with the post. The reason this works so
well is because it creates a little
flywheel. So, you can only get the asset
if you comment and engage. As more
people comment and engage, the algorithm
sees that engagement and shows the post
to more people. And as more people see
it, more people comment and engage, and
it just repeats. We have had some viral
drops get hundreds of thousands of
views, attracting thousands of new email
subscribers into our various funnels.
And as soon as we started seeing this
marketing tactic work, we ramped up the
volume as much as possible. We went from
doing these like once a month to once a
week to multiple times per week. That
said, little context, a lot of people
are very hip to this tactic now, and
we're already seeing diminishing returns
with it about a year later. So, when you
see a tactic working, you should exploit
it, but also keep your eyes out for the
next arbitrage opportunity, because the
one that you currently have will not
last forever. Lesson number 12, the best
managers are intrapreneurs and
incentivized accordingly. You enter the
valley of death as soon as your company
crosses about 15 employees. And the
reason is because as a solo founder or a
pair of co-founders, below 15 employees
you can still manage your whole team.
But once you cross around 15 team
members, it gets to be too much, which
means you need managers. The problem
with managers or department heads is
they are typically pure costs. So their
job is not really revenue critical, it's
more organizational, making sure that
the business continues operating at a
certain standard and doesn't break. They
also tend to be expensive hires because
in order to be a manager, you need to
have enough working knowledge to manage
the people doing the doing, right? And
all of these costs fall directly to the
bottom line. So the business goes
through this valley of death period
where in order to grow further, say
beyond 15 employees, you need department
heads. But the department heads are pure
costs, and those pure costs have an
immediately negative impact on your
business's profit in the short term,
which means to get back to the same
level of profitability or more, you need
to grow beyond the capacity that you've
just opened up within your business.
This is why you hear entrepreneurs talk
about how their business at 10 team
members was more profitable than their
business at 30 team members because as
soon as you enter that valley of death,
there is no middle ground. You either
expand the capacity of the business and
successfully grow through to the other
side or you don't. And if you don't,
then it doesn't make sense to have that
entire layer of management in the
middle. Now building on this, all of
these problems are compounded when your
managers are not intrapreneurs. So over
the years, I have learned that there are
typically two types of managers. I call
them blockers and builders. Blockers are
managers whose value is protecting the
team, the team's time, making sure what
needs to get done gets done. They are
fantastic at keeping an existing machine
operating. Blockers tend to be better
for departments that have already been
built. They don't change much, they just
need structure, they just need
accountability. Builders are the
complete opposite. Builders are managers
whose value is building a department
from scratch or scaling a department
from its current stage to an entirely
new level. Building managers are
typically more entrepreneurial and have
already built the thing you need them to
build somewhere else. So, in this case,
you're really not hiring them to manage
an existing thing, you're hiring them to
build something new, and you're buying
their pattern recognition for how to do
so successfully. Generally speaking,
once your company crosses 15 full-time
employees and you enter that valley of
death, it is a mistake to hire blockers
instead of builders because if every
department is still dependent upon you
to make the strategic decisions, then
you remain the company's biggest
bottleneck. A company can only
successfully scale through that valley
of death when each department has a
builder at the helm capable of growing
it to the next level on their own.
Lesson number 13, whatever gets your
attention grows and everything else
atrophies. A painful lesson I continue
to learn is that as long as you are the
CEO and or primary operator, you cannot
grow multiple things at the same time.
You can't grow multiple businesses at
the same time. You can't grow multiple
departments at the same time. You can't
grow multiple marketing channels at the
same time. The only way that you can
grow multiple different things at the
same time is if you have separate,
self-sufficient, and properly
incentivized operators in charge of each
individual one. And even then, the
person has to have founder potential.
It's really not about how hard they work
or how much they care. It's about
whether or not they can successfully
grow something on their own with minimal
to literally zero involvement from you.
If that's the case and if you have the
resources to make that sort of bet on
someone, then yes, it is possible to
grow something in parallel. But, the
vast majority of the time, people rush
this type of decision and don't realize
that they are still the primary
operator, which means in any given
season of life and business, you have to
decide the priority and there cannot be
multiple priorities. Priority means one,
the most important. The good news is
whatever you decide to be the most
important will grow. Anything that gets
the majority of your attention will
grow. It just will. Most things in life
are simply the result of effort, and
effort is the result of attention. So,
more attention equals more effort equals
more growth. The bad news is deciding
one thing is the most important also
means deciding a handful of other things
are less important. And anything that
gets less of your attention will either
tread water and maintain its current
level or more likely begin to atrophy. I
have seen this happen over and over
again inside our business. Whenever we
pick a new marketing channel to focus on
and prioritize, our other marketing
channels performance stays about the
same and then starts to slowly go down.
Whenever we pick a new product or a new
offer to focus on and we make that the
priority, our other products and our
other offers begin to go down in
revenue. And whenever we pick a new
department to focus on and we say this
is the priority, we're going to build
this department, our other departments
standard begins to dip, right? More
things slip through the cracks,
performance begins to go down. There is
no avoiding this problem, which is why
business is mostly a game of choosing
what trade is worth it at any given
time. Because anytime you prioritize or
gain one thing, you will sacrifice and
begin to lose another. Lesson number 14,
customers don't want more information,
they want better results faster with
less work. This is one of those things
that sounds very simple, but in practice
is incredibly hard to execute and keep
top of mind. When you're selling any
kind of info product or running a cohort
or you have a training program, your
impulse is to give customers everything.
You want to tell them everything you
know. You want to explain every little
nuance. You want to share random
tangential facts or insights or just
interesting information. And that's
because you yourself believe everything
is important. The problem is nobody
wakes up in the morning excited to learn
everything. In fact, what customers want
way more than to learn is to succeed.
They don't actually care or want to know
how the sausage gets made. They just
want the sausage, and they want it right
now with minimal effort. And if that
sounds like a hard thing to deliver,
that's because it is. Customers value
less information, but faster, more
guaranteed results way more than they do
lots of information, but slower, more
ambiguous results. So, this means that
you have to spend more time thinking
about what to remove rather than what to
add. Do customers really need 10
modules? How can you give them what they
need in three modules? Do customers
really need eight live sessions? How
could you accomplish all of this in a
single hour? Do customers really need to
know all of these things? How can you
give them a checklist to complete to
accomplish the same end result in a
fraction of the time? Over and over
again, I continue to learn this lesson.
Customers don't actually want more
stuff. What they want is a higher ROI on
their time and their effort, leading to
better results faster. By the way, this
is fundamentally why you see so many
people selling AI prompts and cloud
skills now, because in this case, you're
not selling information. What you're
selling is copy-paste this thing to get
the same result I get, except in 30
seconds with zero work. That's why it's
such a compelling offer. Lesson number
15, don't anchor your business's profit
or your personal income to your highest
performing month. Every step function
change in business profit and or
personal income changes the way you see
the world. So, when I was making 10
grand per month in personal income, I
thought 20 grand a month was
life-changing money. Then, when I was
making 20 grand a month, I thought 40
grand a month was life-changing money.
Then, when I was making 40 grand a
month, I thought 80 grand a month was
life-changing money. And you probably
know where this is going. When I was
making 80 grand a month, I thought 160
grand a month was life-changing money.
The goalpost never stops moving. The
problem is, if you anchor yourself to
your businesses highest performing
month, then you will begin to make
decisions in your life assuming that
that peak won't go away. And if I've
learned anything in business, it is that
what goes up usually comes back down,
and what comes down usually goes back
up. I made a whole YouTube video about
this idea, which I like to call the
genius idiot roller coaster. When you're
up, you think you're a genius. When
you're down, you think you're an idiot.
And neither extreme is true. So, don't
make forward-leaning decisions based on
your peak months. Instead, make
decisions based on a rolling 12-month
average. So, this goes for hiring
decisions inside your business, and this
goes for personal finance decisions
based on your personal income. You never
want to make forward-leaning decisions
based on an outlier month or an outlier
quarter. Lesson number 16, if you truly
want to scale your business, you have to
be motivated by more than just money.
Full transparency, the decision we made
in 2023 to move away from running Ship
30 for 30 cohorts and begin building our
premium Ghost Journey Academy began one
of the hardest and most taxing work
chapters I have experienced to date as
an entrepreneur. And yes, part of this
decision was based on money. We felt we
had reached a plateau running Ship 30
for 30 as our core business and wanted
to pursue a new, potentially more
lucrative business model, high-ticket
group coaching. Now, looking back, I can
say this was false. We just didn't know
how to do what we were doing better at
the time. So, we did what everyone does,
which is decide to start something new.
But I can only see that in hindsight.
But the primary motivator for building
PGA, at least for me, was that I wanted
to level up as an entrepreneur. I wanted
to take on more risk. I wanted to hold
myself to a higher standard. I wanted to
try to scale something again. I wanted
to build new skills. I wanted to put
myself in a position where my deficits
would be forced to grow and improve. So,
my primary motivator for building PGA
was not to make more money. And I think
to scale any business to a meaningful
level, meaningful being like high seven
figures or eight figures and above,
money can't be the only motivator
because it's too hard. Over the past 3
years, I have experienced a tremendous
amount of responsibility and stress.
Just for context, I'm already a
millionaire. So, incrementally more
money is no longer motivating for me.
What is motivating is knowing that I'm
growing, even if it's painful. So, if
you haven't achieved some level of
financial abundance in your life yet and
or you don't value building the skills
that come with high-risk
entrepreneurship, you are much better
off not scaling your business because
oftentimes scaling your business does
not mean that you make more money and
certainly not right away. Scaling often
means sacrifice and making less money in
the short term, valley of death, in
hopes of making more money later. So, if
your only motivation is making more
money now, then don't scale. Just stay
small, stack a little bit of profit, buy
some Bitcoin if you want add a flavor of
risk, not financial advice, and enjoy
the fact that you operate a small
business and cash flow machine that pays
for your life and then some. You should
only scale if your motivation to grow is
more than just money. Lesson 17, info
plus software plus coaching equals
compounding profit. One of the things we
got accidentally right building Ship 30
for 30 is we created a stack of offers
that all compounded on each other. I
want to be very clear, we did not do
this intentionally.
We didn't really understand what we were
doing at the time. This was done very
intuitively and just happened to be the
right answer. I can only see the
framework now in hindsight. So, Ship 30
for 30 was a cohort-based writing
challenge. This was the info component.
Yes, we were also selling
accountability, writing with other
people, it was gamified, etc., but
people were mostly buying how to write
online education paired with this
accountability. TypeShare was the SaaS
platform that we built with founder Sam
Shaw to pair with it. So, inside of Ship
30, we taught people how to write atomic
essays online and then we built the
software to help them write and design
their own atomic essays. So, the info
fed the software. On the back of Ship
30, we launched a back-end upsell called
Captain's Table. And this was like a
lightweight community mastermind for
Ship 30 graduates who wanted access to
more education and more live sessions
with us. So, all of these things
together created a pretty amazing
flywheel. Ship 30 was a profitable
business in itself, but Ship 30 also
meant that we profitably acquired
TypeShare customers. TypeShare customers
became a secondary source of recurring
revenue. And Ship 30 and TypeShare's
customers both became the people most
likely to join Captain's Table. So,
whenever I'm building info products or
programs now, I think about how to
replicate this stack of offers. And a
few years later, we did this within our
Premium Ghostwriting Academy, too. PGA
was a high-ticket group coaching
program, so this was the info component.
Inside PGA, we educated students on how
to use AI to help them land clients and
fulfill on client work using our own
software called Ghost Space. This was
the software component. And then, we
would upsell PGA students and Ghost
Space users to our back-end program,
Lift Off. This was the continued
coaching component. Especially in the
age of AI where you can vibe code custom
software, you should think of software
as a highly congruent and niche-down
product that you can include in your
offer stack. The info component educates
people on how to use the software. The
software retains your power users, and
your power users are the ones you upsell
to coaching. Lesson number 18, your team
members watch what you do more than they
listen to what you say. In 2025, our
team grew from around 15 full-time team
members to over 30 full-time team
members. So, in September, we did like
900,000 in revenue and ran our first
Ship 30 cohort in over a year. In
October, we did little over 700,000 in
revenue and continued running weekly 2
and 1/2 hour free webinars to drive
people to PGA. In November, we did like
850,000 in revenue and ran a huge 3-day
ghostwriting challenge, simultaneously
building our Black Friday product.
November was nuts. And in December, we
did a little over 800,000 in revenue
while still running weekly webinars,
expanding the video production team, and
recording like 1 to 2 months worth of
content proactively through the
holidays. I can confidently say that
September to December 2025 is one of the
most taxing stretches I have ever put
myself through as an entrepreneur. The
business also did the most revenue it
had ever done in four consecutive
months. So, good example of how results
tend to follow extreme effort. But,
after all of that early December, I
decided that the best thing for the
business was not for me to take my foot
off the gas. Most people chill in
December. They throw in the towel, it's
the end of the year, they're just going
to coast into Christmas. I typically do
the opposite, but especially this year,
I chose to not do that. After that
entire stretch and pushing to build an
entire new product for Black Friday
while having COVID, while doing this
3-day challenge, while running weekly
webinars, I blocked two entire weeks off
my calendar to do nothing except hold
one-on-ones with all 30-plus team
members. Our team had grown a lot in
2025, and we had just pushed everyone
through like a hardcore season of
intensity. So, I felt like it was
important to go above and beyond for
each and every person and lead by
example. And I can't tell you how many
team members told me afterwards how much
they appreciated it and how rare it is
for the CEO to still be so in the weeds
even as the company grows through
multiple layers of management. So, it
was a really good reminder of how much
people pay attention to your actions and
what you do much more than the things
you say but do not embody yourself.
Lesson number 19, as soon as you know
what to do, stop consuming content. I'm
saying this to myself as much as I'm
saying this to you. As soon as you know
what to do, the value of consumption
falls off a cliff. The entire point of
consumption, at least through the lens
of productivity, is to gather
information and build pattern
recognition of what actions to take that
will lead to the outcome you desire.
But, as soon as you know what those
actions are, and you have a general
sense of how to do them, then the value
of more consumption goes down. At that
point, consumption is no longer a
benefit. It is actually a distraction.
The seasons of business where I have
experienced the most progress are also
the seasons where I have consumed the
least amount of new content and taken
consistent action in a chosen direction.
And, not surprisingly, the seasons of
business where I have experienced the
least amount of progress are also the
seasons where I have consumed too much
or consumed too many different things,
causing me to chase too many different
aspirations and take the least
consistent action in any chosen
direction. The only time I have ever
found high consumption to be productive
is when you have maxed out more of what
you're currently doing, but you aren't
yet sure how to do it better. When this
is the case, the right decision is to
consume lots of different ideas and
frameworks and ways of thinking so you
can decide what's worth prioritizing
inside of your existing vehicle. But
where this becomes a mistake is when you
max out more, you've maxed out effort
you think you have, and then you go
consume lots of different ideas and ways
of thinking so you can entertain all the
new and different things that you could
possibly do. And very quickly, this
turns into productive procrastination
and shiny object overload. Consumption
should always be in service of taking
the right actions in a specific chosen
direction. If not, then consumption
works against you. And lesson 20, every
time you change what you want, you
disrupt compounding and start over. This
is probably the lesson that I've been
thinking about the most. I became an
entrepreneur in September 2016. That is
when I quit my 9-to-5 job and went all
in on working for myself. Since then, I
have changed what I wanted
>> [laughter]
>> more times than I'd care to admit. So,
end of 2016, when I quit my job, all I
wanted was to pay my rent as a freelance
writer and ghostwriter and work toward
becoming a full-time author. That's what
I wanted. Then in 2017, I changed what I
wanted and decided to scale my
ghostwriting work into an agency and
build a real business. Then in 2018, I
changed what I wanted and decided to
bring on two angel investors inside my
agency and try to scale to the moon as
this like hybrid agency and software
startup, which was a monumental mistake.
In 2020, I changed what I wanted,
decided I didn't want to run a high-risk
startup or agency anymore, fired
everyone, downsized, and went back to
being a highly paid solopreneur. At this
point, I circled back and said, "I want
to work toward being a full-time
author." I went back to my original
want. Then in 2021, I changed what I
wanted and decided to scale Ship 30 for
30 with Dickie and build another
business and paid newsletter at the same
time called Category Pirates. Then in
2023, I changed what I wanted and exited
Category Pirates after growing it to
multi-seven-figure business in like 2
years and decided that I wanted to build
a more advanced business with Dickie,
which is when we started PGA, our
Premium Go Training Academy. And in
2025, I changed what I wanted and
decided I wanted to try and scale PGA to
the moon and spent hundreds of thousands
of dollars on joining masterminds and
spent millions of dollars running paid
ads. I decided I want to play that game.
And I remember making each of these
decisions. At the time, it seemed like
the right decision based on the
information and skills that I had. But
looking back, I can see now the pattern
with significantly more clarity. Every
time you change what you want, you
essentially start over. You disrupt
compounding of your previous want and
you swap it for something else. So, as I
move into this next chapter of life and
business, this is a lesson I'm taking to
heart. I'm thinking about this a lot and
I'm trying very hard to only play games
that I can see myself playing for 10
years or more. Now, obviously, if I
acquire new information and decide the
right decision is to change course,
right, change what I want, I will. But
after a decade of being an entrepreneur,
I can't help but wonder where I would be
today if I hadn't changed what I wanted
so many times and just committed to the
same goal for 10 years instead of
changing goals every 2 or 3 years.